Hi, my name is Dave Schoeneck and we're talking about how you're going to feel after your first day of adaptive skiing.
In some of the things to prepare would be obviously some upper body stretching.
Upper body and abdominal exercises.
That always helps in preparation but after the first day you might be a little sore.
You probably will use muscles that you haven't used before but with that soreness will come a tremendous amount of exuberance and having fun.
At having being out on the mountain and just you wont be able to wait until you can get back up and ski again.
But again, the more and more you can prepare any of your upper body muscles and with weights and stretching the better off you're going to be.
Some of the muscles that you'll use would be obviously your forearms, your biceps, your lats, your back.
There'll be a number of things you will, can't find muscles that you didn't, forgot you even had but those are really the upper body is doing a awful lot of the work for you and then you just let the ski do the rest of the work.
So but again the biggest thing that you're going to think about after your first day is not the aching muscles.
It's going to be how much fun you had and you just wont be able to wait until you get back up and do it again.